<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bioconductor on seandavi(s12)</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/tags/bioconductor/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bioconductor on seandavi(s12)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Sean Davis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/tags/bioconductor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Matched tumor/normal pairs--a use case for the GenomicDataCommons Bioconductor package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/03/matched-tumor/normal-pairs--a-use-case-for-the-genomicdatacommons-bioconductor-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/03/matched-tumor/normal-pairs--a-use-case-for-the-genomicdatacommons-bioconductor-package/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The NCI Genomic Data Commons (GDC) is a reboot of the approach that NCI uses to manage and expose genomic and associated clinical and experimental metadata. I have been working on a Bioconductor package that interfaces with the GDC API to provide search and data retrieval from within R.
testing In the first of what will likely be a set of use cases for the GenomicDataCommons, I am going to address a question that came up on twitter from @sleight82</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GenomicDataCommons Package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/project/genomicdatacommons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/project/genomicdatacommons/</guid>
      <description>The National Cancer Institute (NCI) has established the Genomic Data Commons (GDC). The GDC provides the cancer research community with an open and unified repository for sharing and accessing data across numerous cancer studies and projects via a high-performance data transfer and query infrastructure. The GenomicDataCommons Bioconductor package provides basic infrastructure for querying, accessing, and mining genomic datasets available from the GDC. We expect that the Bioconductor developer and the larger bioinformatics communities will build on the GenomicDataCommons package to add higher-level functionality and expose cancer genomics data to the plethora of state-of-the-art bioinformatics methods available in Bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>