<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on seandavi(s12)</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on seandavi(s12)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Sean Davis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A computable Bioconductor build report</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/11/a-computable-bioconductor-build-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/11/a-computable-bioconductor-build-report/</guid>
      <description>Bioconductor spends a substantial amount of effort to build its catalog of software each day. Reporting of these results is critical for developers, users, and project leaders to understand the software “health” of the project.
The Bioconductor build reports are generally available as html pages that are navigable with bookmarks and link out to detailed reports of errors, etc. However, the build reports are not readily computable, so mining the reports, automated processing by developers, and learning about failure modes automatically is challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClinicalTrialsAPI R package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/project/clinical-trials-gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/project/clinical-trials-gov/</guid>
      <description> [Project Site]  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GenomicDataCommons Package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/project/genomicdatacommons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/project/genomicdatacommons/</guid>
      <description>The National Cancer Institute (NCI) has established the Genomic Data Commons (GDC). The GDC provides the cancer research community with an open and unified repository for sharing and accessing data across numerous cancer studies and projects via a high-performance data transfer and query infrastructure. The GenomicDataCommons Bioconductor package provides basic infrastructure for querying, accessing, and mining genomic datasets available from the GDC. We expect that the Bioconductor developer and the larger bioinformatics communities will build on the GenomicDataCommons package to add higher-level functionality and expose cancer genomics data to the plethora of state-of-the-art bioinformatics methods available in Bioconductor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The cRomwell R package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/project/cromwell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/project/cromwell/</guid>
      <description> [Project Site]  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>