<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on seandavi(s12)</title>
    <link>https://seandavi.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on seandavi(s12)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Sean Davis</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://seandavi.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a basic Apache Spark cluster in the cloud (in 5 minutes)</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2018/02/create-a-basic-apache-spark-cluster-in-the-cloud-in-5-minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2018/02/create-a-basic-apache-spark-cluster-in-the-cloud-in-5-minutes/</guid>
      <description>Apache Spark is a software and data science platform that is purpose-built for large- to massive-scale data processing. Spark supports processing of data in batch mode (run as a pipeline) or in interactive mode using command-line programming style or in popular notebook style of coding. While scala is the native language for Spark, language bindings exist for python, R, and Java as well.
Spark is built around an underlying data abstraction called Resilient Distributed Dataset, or RDD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agricultural genomics may benefit from human genomic data and software engineering</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/11/agricultural-genomics-may-benefit-from-human-genomic-data-and-software-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/post/2017/11/agricultural-genomics-may-benefit-from-human-genomic-data-and-software-engineering/</guid>
      <description>As a government employee, I have been given some fantastic opportunities to interact with other government employees and agencies doing really important research in service to the country. Over the past couple of days, I have been attending a great symposium to provide an updated Blueprint for animal genetics and genomics. Discussion was wide-ranging, but largely focused on genomics, informatics, and translation to and from phenotypes. High-throughput phenotyping (think wearables for plants and cows and drone videos of cattle herds) seems like a growth area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClinicalTrialsAPI R package</title>
      <link>https://seandavi.github.io/project/clinical-trials-gov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://seandavi.github.io/project/clinical-trials-gov/</guid>
      <description> [Project Site]  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>